HARSHDEEP SINGH

https://harshdeeply.netlify.app/

https://www.linkedin.com/in/harshdeep-singh-71b98b185/

Highlights

- ★ An undergrad student studying at BCIT School of Computing and Academic Studies
- ★ Highly ambitious and passionate self-learner
- ★ Experience in pair programming and agile software development
- ★ Experience in UI/UX development

Technical Skills

Languages	Tools	Libraries/Platforms	SQA	Database	
HTML/CSS	Slack	React/Angular	Automated testing	MongoDB	
JavaScript	Trello/Jira	React Native/Ionic	Writing test cases	MySQL	
Python	Git	Node.js	Documenting reports	Firebase	

Work Experience

★ Zeniox, Montréal, QB

May 2020 - September 2020

harshdeepkairon@yahoo.com

Technical Support Agent (Part-time, remote)

- Provide daily support to users of various computer systems including answering questions, analyzing problems, and quickly forming solutions to return systems to proper operation
- Maintain detailed records of daily interactions with customers, installation activities, reported issues, and completed solution

★ Xorosoft Inc, Burnaby, BC

May 2019 - April 2020

Junior Software Developer (Technical Intern)

- Identify customer needs and help customers use specific features of an ERP software (SaaS)
- Writing and maintaining code for computer/web applications
- Participate in pair-programming to work on bug fixes
- Engage with intermediate/senior developers to learn the codebase and development environment

Technical Project Experience

★ Portfolio Website

- Created my personal portfolio website using ReactJS and Gatsby
- Deployed on Netlify via GitHub

★ ReactJS calculator (Personal Project)

October 2020 - October 2020

- Created a calculator using ReactJS as a personal project
- Got knowledge about how components work and interact with each other using props and callbacks
- Learnt about how react hooks interact with the application

★ ReactJS Todo app (Personal project)

September 2020 - Present

- Created a Todo App using ReactJS as a class project
- Learnt about how react hooks interact with the application
- Implemented theme switching and react router to allow routing in React
- The application is still under development but the code can be seen <u>here</u>

Education

★ British Columbia Institute of Technology

January 2019 - December 2020

Computer Information Technology (Post Secondary Diploma)

- Web Development and Designing
- UI/UX Designing
- Database Administration
- Algorithms and Data Structures
- Mobile Application Development

Hackathons

★ NASA Space Apps COVID-19 Challenge

May 2020

 Worked in a team of 6 on hacking for the COVID-19 pandemic where we used the NASA satellite data to plot the green land (parks in our case) and based on algorithms, the program outputs a "risk-rating" number that marks the risk percentage for different parks

★ Justice Hack

November 2019

 Worked in a team of 5 on extracting data using python from public judicial sources to accumulate it and present the statistics.

★ Vanhacks October 2019

- Worked on developing a web-based application for a non-profit organization helping people who are less fortunate by allowing them to locate nearby vital resources such as shelter, free food, toilets, free clothes, etc.
- Used ReactJS to develop the PWA